studentvip.com.au 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy – StudentVIP

  1. Privacy

Last updated 17 July 2012

Purpose Personal information is collected to create and fund relevant and useful services for students. 

Our aim is to have all collection of your personal information be transparent and controlled by you.

Australian legislation StudentVIP complies with the Privacy Act (1988), The 13 Australian Privacy Principles and the Spam Act (2003). Your information will not be held outside Australia. 

Not collected information We do not collect any personal information about: racial or ethnic origins, political opinions or memberships, religious beliefs or sexual preferences, union membership or health or genetic information. 

Why personal information is collected We have made the effort to allow you to see why each piece of personal information is collected at the My Account page. 

You control publicly displayed information Some personal information is displayed publicly when you choose to use Textbookexchange, Studentflatmates and other services. You will know which personal information is seen publicly and which is not. 

Who has your personal information StudentVIP is owned by Student Services Australia Pty Linited acn 100 372 156. When we send you StudentVIP email alerts on behalf of another organisation, that organisation does not have your personal information. Your personal information is only held by us and our third party service providers directly required to provide our services to you. 

Unsubscribing All email correspondence sent to you will identify who it is from and will have a functional unsubscribe link in the footer. You can also unsubscribe from the entire family of StudentVIP site at any time via the unsubscribe link on StudentVIP. 

Privacy Officer StudentVIP's Privacy Officer is Andrew Maloney. Please contact Andrew with any questions or concerns regarding StudentVIP and privacy. Andrew is contactable via email. firstname [at] studentservices.com.au or by the "Feedback" link at the bottom of each page. 

Spam StudentVIP does not send out unsolicited email (Spam). 

Website usage data Like most websites, StudentVIP maintains log files tracking IP addresses to analyse trends, help diagnose problems with our servers, and to monitor traffic/usage in order to provide better service to our members. StudentVIP uses cookies to improve the our members' experience when using our websites. You can always choose to not accept cookies, but in doing so you may not be able to use our websites effectively. Some of our business partners, such as our Web analytics provider, also use cookies on our site. These cookies are used to track visitor behaviour, and StudentVIP has no access to or control over these cookies. 

Email usage data To improve our services, StudentVIP uses pixel tags and other methods to gather information about the emails it sends to members. Pixel tags allow StudentVIP to record and store information such as date and time the recipient viewed the email message, if the recipient's email program is capable of receiving HTML, and other information. 

Location data The Lost on Campus app uses your mobile phone's location to display your current location on your campus map. Your location is only visible to you and is not disclosed to other users. You may turn this feature off, however, you will not be able to see where you are on the map. 

Personal Information This is defined by the Privacy Act. 

Links to other websites StudentVIP is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other web sites. 

Changes to this policy Under the site terms, SSA may change these policies at any time, with immediate effect. 

Contact us If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, you should first contact the Privacy Officer at the contact address listed below. 

Chief Privacy Officer  
Student Services Australia  
56 Meagher Street  
Chippendale NSW 2008

Phone: (02) 9698 4999
